My name is Alick and his is Tengere.
I am Kazakh and in this country, I am called the father of birds.
Tengere has lived with me for ten years.
I found it here.
in these mountains,
between China and the Russian Empire.
It was a winter morning.
Tengere's wings were trapped in the ice.
They could no longer fly.
I brought it home.
I got him used to my presence and over time,
He became my friend.
I've had other eagles before him.
My father had some too.
And my father's father.
They lived, like me,
by hunting and selling pots.
They taught me to read in the flight of birds.
For centuries,
The Kazakhs ruled over Central Asia.
With wars and invasions,
We have lost our land and some of our knowledge.
what time
In a few days,
Tengere will leave me.
He will regain his freedom.
He must go back up there.
near his family.
To find a partner and have children.
Before they leave,
I want them to help me pass on to my son the ancient wisdom of the Kazakhs.
life with the big birds and winters in the mountains.
My son Oulam is now old enough to carry an eagle,
And my role was to teach him the secrets of our family.
And for that,
I must capture another eagle,
and when it is erected,
I will bring my son.
I will show him the lands of our ancestors.
The Land of the Wind and the Kingdom of the Eagles.
Around a hundred eagles live in this territory.
But they are wary.
They know the Russians like men.
He must be two years old.
Go to Tengere,
Help me trap him.
The eagle is a proud bird.
He goes crazy when he gets caught in the trap.
Grief, on the other hand, burns inside the body.
To extinguish this fire,
I need to pour cold water down the back of his throat.
Without that,
He could die.
My name is Riketan,
like this mountain where I captured it.
I don't like the first few days of training.
Greg is upset.
He is afraid of the man.
He doesn't understand.
I have to tire him out to the very end of his strength so that he will accept me and forget his pain.
I spend little time with my family.
I love them,
but on the farm,
The Eagles are too dangerous.
I don't want them to get used to the noise of men.
I want them to remain pure and wild.
THANKS.
The initial training lasts a few days.
I need to get Ketan used to hunting with me right away.
He needs to understand that I am his friend.
that I don't want to hide his prey from him,
And above all, that we can and must work together.
I reassure Ketan.
I tell him that he is the most beautiful of birds and that he can eat by my side.
Without fear,
I never approach him from the front.
The eagle does not like the face of man,
He prefers his profile.
Every one of my movements must be precise and controlled.
I never get along with it.
My son Ulan needs to learn all of this.
It will be a long process.
But Tengere will help him.
"Ethan now agrees to sit on my arm."
Tomorrow,
He will be ready and we will leave.
Ketan will come with me and Ulan will take Tengere.
Leaving with my son,
It's an old dream of mine.
An old dream of Khasar's.
He wants to maintain the traditions.
In the mountains,
Tengere and I have a language.
I inherited it from my ancestors.
Now,
it's my son's turn to take it.
This
sound is that of dying prey.
All of Tengere's power is concentrated in its talons.
He is tense.
ready to attack.
I'm taking you to the land of our ancestors.
The story
of our people is very ancient.
Our legends tell of our connection with the bird people.
Formerly,
The Kazars could tame them all.
Some even knew their language.
Today,
We are now only a handful.
Tengere
and I are partners.
They hunt,
pots are selling,
They eat meat.
For us,
the Kassas,
the sacred Church.
It is both the beauty and the harshness of the world.
Here,
Each eagle reigns over a territory.
And they defend him.
sometimes even to the point of death.
Here,
Many Kazakhs perished because they were defending their territory.
Near an eagle,
Life is wonderful.
Like with a child.
For the past ten years,
I never left Tengere.
I fed him,
I took care of him.
And now,
He's going to leave.
The season of love begins.
Tengere will find a wife.
He will have a son and he will tell him the stories of men.
Tengere has to leave now, and that's fine.
Go
Tengere,
Don't come back.
One last thing,
Remember that the eagle is the only creature that can look directly at the sun without burning its eyes.